jaxtr.com 2012-11-10

# jaxtr - privacy policy

Last modified: February 25, 2008:

Recent updates to this Privacy Policy

## About jaxtr

Jaxtr is a social communications service provided at www.jaxtr.com and its directly associated domains and widgets (collectively, "jaxtr" or "Service"). This Privacy Policy explains what information of yours will be collected by jaxtr and how such information will be used. By using or accessing jaxtr, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. 

Jaxtr cares deeply about online privacy. If you have any questions concerning this privacy policy, please contact us in writing by visiting our [Support site](http://support.jaxtr.com/index.php?departmentid=5&_m=tickets&step=1&_a=submit&subject=Privacy_Issue).

## Information Collection and Use by jaxtr

When you visit jaxtr you provide us with two types of information: personal information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected by us, and Service use information collected by us as you interact with our Service.

When you register with jaxtr, you provide us with certain personal information, such as your name, your email address, your telephone number, your age, your gender, language and any other personal or preference information that you provide to us. Jaxtr collects user submitted information to provide the Service, authenticate users, and send notifications relating to the Service. By providing jaxtr your email address you consent to our using the email address to send you Service-related notices, including any notices required by law, in lieu of communication by postal mail. We may also use your email address to send you other messages, such as updates, user communications, newsletters, changes to features of the Service, or jaxtr offers. If you do not want to receive certain email or text messages, you may opt out by visiting our [Support site](http://support.jaxtr.com/index.php?departmentid=13&_m=tickets&step=1&_a=submit&subject=Member_Block_Me_Request). Opting out may prevent you from receiving valuable messages regarding updates, improvements, offers, or communications from other users. Jaxtr reserves the right to send you notices about your account even if you opt out of all voluntary email notifications.

When you visit jaxtr, we collect your browser type and IP address. This information is gathered for all jaxtr visitors. In addition, we store certain information from your browser using "cookies." A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer tied to information about the user. We use session ID cookies to confirm that users are logged in. These cookies terminate once the user closes the browser. By default, we use a persistent cookie that stores your login ID (but not your password), email address and phone number to make it easier for you to use the Service. You can remove or block this cookie using the settings in your browser if you want to disable this convenient feature. Some features of the Service may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled. Please note that jaxtr may allow third party advertisers that are presenting advertisements on some of our pages to set and access their cookies on your computer. Advertisers' use of cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not the jaxtr Privacy Policy.

Jaxtr provides all members with a Contact page that is publicly viewable by default. Jaxtr displays certain information, including members' pictures, country, age range, names, and friends' names and pictures on the Service in order to facilitate user interaction. You may control and change the information displayed on your Contact page from your Account page. Note that your private phone number and email address is hidden from other users by default. To facilitate searching and finding interesting content on the Service, jaxtr may allow users to search for other members using first and last name, phone number, email address, and other standard search strategies. Even if you choose the "private" setting for your Contact page to prevent others from viewing it, your name, country and picture thumbnail may be available in search results and those limited pieces of information may be made available to third party search engines.

Jaxtr may also collect information about you from other sources, such as public profiles, newspapers, blogs, instant messaging services, and other users of the jaxtr Service through the operation of the service (e.g., tags) in order to provide you with more useful information and a more personalized experience.

Jaxtr will not share your personally identifiable information with others except in limited circumstances where we believe such sharing is reasonably necessary to offer the Service, legally required or, permitted by you. For example, we may provide information to service providers to help us bring you the services we offer. Specifically, we may use third parties to facilitate our business, such as to host the Service at a co-location facility for servers, to send out email updates about jaxtr, to remove repetitive information from our user lists, to process payments for products or services, or to provide search results or links (including sponsored links). In connection with these offerings and business operations, our service providers may have access to your personal information for use for a limited time. Where we utilize third parties for the processing of any personal information, we implement reasonable contractual and technical protections limiting the use of that information to the jaxtr-specified purposes. We may store personal information in locations outside the direct control of jaxtr (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers).

We save the information gathered through your use of the Service. We collect this information so that we can provide you our services and offer personalized features. In most cases, we retain it so that, for instance, you can return to view prior communications or easily see your friend list. When you update information, we usually keep a backup copy of the prior version for a reasonable period of time to enable reversion to the prior version of that information.

## Invitations and Other Communications to Non-members

Jaxtr members can invite other people to join the service by sending invitation emails via our automated invitation system. Jaxtr stores the email addresses that members provide so that the respondents may be added to the contacts list of the member sending the invitations, and also to send reminders of the invitations. Jaxtr does not sell these email addresses or use them to send any other communication besides invitations and invitation reminders. Recipients of invitations from jaxtr may contact jaxtr to request that no more invitations be sent to them from a particular member or from all members.

Jaxtr members may also store contact information of people they know in their internal jaxtr address book and may also choose to send invitations and other communications to those addresses.

## Your Communications on jaxtr

You may use jaxtr to initiate or receive phone calls, email, IM, text or SMS messages which are partly or fully handled via jaxtr telecommunications or messaging partners. Any information which you may communicate during such interactions, including any personal information, may be handled by jaxtr telecommunications or messaging partners and shall not be deemed private. Jaxtr cannot guarantee the security of information that you disclose or communicate in such phone calls and you do so at your own risk. Jaxtr discloses your telephone number to its telecommunications or messaging partners in order to provide the Service.

We may permit third party advertisers to sponsor certain features of jaxtr, such as text messaging. When a third party sponsors a jaxtr feature, advertisements for or by that sponsor may appear in connection with your communications over the Service that use that feature.

Jaxtr automatically creates archives of your messages and call history on the Service. To the extent not otherwise required by law, we will purge your archives after a reasonable period of time.

## Non-Personally Identifiable Information

Jaxtr logs non-personally identifiable information such as IP address, time zone, profile information, aggregate user data, and browser type, from users and visitors to the site. Such data are used to manage the website, track usage and improve the website services. This non-personally identifiable information may be shared with third parties to provide more relevant services and advertisements to users. User IP addresses are also recorded for security and monitoring purposes.

When you use the Service, we may employ clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons) which are used to track the online usage patterns of our users anonymously. No personally identifiable information from your jaxtr account is collected using these clear gifs. In addition, we may also use clear gifs in HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened by recipients. The information is used to enable more accurate reporting, improve the effectiveness of our marketing, and make jaxtr better for our users.

Jaxtr may use certain information about you without identifying you as an individual to third parties. We do this for purposes such as analyzing how the Service is used, diagnosing service or technical problems, maintaining security, and personalizing advertisements and promotions.

## Links

Jaxtr may contain links to other sites. Jaxtr is not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices on other sites. When following a link to another site from jaxtr, you should read the privacy policy stated on that site. Our Privacy Policy only governs information collected on jaxtr.

## Public Postings

Please be aware that whenever you voluntarily post or communicate information in public areas of the jaxtr Service, that information can be accessed and stored by the public, and may in turn be used by those people to send you unsolicited communications.

## Correcting/Updating or Removing Information

Jaxtr members may modify or update their personal account information at any time by logging into their account and accessing the Account page. You can also review, correct or request the removal of the information about you that jaxtr keeps on file by contacting us via our [Support site](http://support.jaxtr.com/index.php?departmentid=13&_m=tickets&step=1&_a=submit&subject=Account_Cancellation_Request). Removed information may persist in backup copies for a reasonable period of time but will not be generally available to members of jaxtr.

Where you make use of the communication features of the Service to share information with others on jaxtr, however, (e.g., sending a text message to another user) you generally cannot remove such communications. 

## Third Party Advertising

Advertisements appearing in connection with our Service may be delivered to users by jaxtr or one of our advertising partners. Our advertising partners may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time the server sends you an online advertisement. In this way, ad servers may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by jaxtr and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. 

## Security

Jaxtr member accounts are secured by member-created passwords. Jaxtr takes reasonable precautions to insure that member account information is kept private and to protect member information that is stored within our database. We restrict access to member information to those employees who need access to perform their job functions, such as our customer service personnel and technical staff. Please note that we cannot guarantee the security of member account information or any other information you transmit to jaxtr and you do so at your own risk. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards, and other factors may compromise the security of member information at any time. For any additional information about the security measures we use on jaxtr, please contact us in writing by visiting our [Support site](http://support.jaxtr.com/index.php?departmentid=14&_m=tickets&step=1&_a=submit&subject=TOS). 

## Sharing and Disclosure of Information jaxtr Collects

Except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, we will not disclose personal information to any third party unless we believe that disclosure is necessary: (1) to conform to legal requirements or to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other legal process received by jaxtr, whether or not a response is required by applicable law; (2) to enforce the jaxtr Terms of Use Agreement or to protect our rights; or (3) to protect the safety or rights of members of the public or users of the Service. Jaxtr reserves the right to transfer personal information to a successor in interest that acquires rights to that information as a result of the sale of jaxtr or substantially all of its assets to that successor in interest. We may also transfer such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, or dissolution.

## Children's Privacy

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, jaxtr does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register. If you are under 13, please do not send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under age 13 is allowed to provide any personal information to or on jaxtr. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us via our [Support site](http://support.jaxtr.com/index.php?departmentid=14&_m=tickets&step=1&_a=submit&subject=COPPA).

## Notification Procedures

It is our policy to provide notifications, whether such notifications are required by law or are for marketing or other business related purposes, to you via email notice, written or hard copy notice, or through conspicuous posting of such notice on our website, as determined by jaxtr in its sole discretion. We reserve the right to determine the form and means of providing notifications to you, provided that you may opt out of certain means of notification as described in this Privacy Policy. In the event that personal information is compromised as a result of a breach of security, jaxtr will promptly notify those persons whose personal information has been compromised, in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law. 

## Changes in Our Privacy Policy

From time to time we may make changes to our privacy policy. If we make changes, we will notify you in this Privacy Policy of what the changes are so users will always be aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and when we may disclose it. Changes to the Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

## Contacting jaxtr

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, please contact us by visiting our [Support site](http://support.jaxtr.com/index.php?departmentid=5&_m=tickets&step=1&_a=submit&subject=Privacy_Issue) or writing us at jaxtr, 82 Pioneer Way, Suite 109, Mountain View, CA 94041, USA.

Last modified: February 25, 2008 

**Updates**

January 16, 2008:
     We added the section “Notification Procedures,” and revised the section “Changes in Our Privacy Policy” to state that changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page. 
February 25, 2008:
     We made revisions throughout the Privacy Policy to reflect jaxtr’s evolving services. 
June 18, 2009:
     We made revisions throughout the Privacy Policy to reflect jaxtr’s address.
